Daniel Sukoneck

daniel@sukoneck.com resume.sukoneck.com

I am a creative devops practitioner whose passion for Web3, automation, and improving user experiences rivals my passion for innovation, team building, and leadership. I have had great opportunities to lead large, constrained, and impactful projects with diverse teams to meet some of the most discerning needs.

Experience

Lead DevOps Engineer, Grand Canyon Education, 2019 - Present

Leader of a team of five engineers doing platform development and process automation using tools primarily from Hashi, AWS, and Azure for a leading higher education managed services provider.

- Developed a global AWS identity and account strategy. Wrote Terraform that managed all resources while also being modular and accessible enough for non-Terraform
 users to use. Built pipelines to enable self-service workflows. Created designs for the same in Azure
- · Rebuilt and transitioned work-tracking boards, backlogs, and processes for multiple teams
- Managed architecture and feature development for ELK logging
- Led the initial phases of creating an IT program management office
- Built pipelines to support custom self-service Puppet architecture

Senior Cloud and Infrastructure Consultant, West Monroe Partners, 2014 - 2019

As a senior consultant at a business and technical consulting firm, I was responsible for executing technical and strategic infrastructure focused consulting engagements and promoting the growth and mentorship of my team.

- Awarded the west coast Consultant of the Year and selected for a mentorship program with executive leadership
- Helped a leading financial institution develop and execute their cloud strategy by creating a two-year migration roadmap. Developed architecture designs for more than 50 applications. Led as many as 15 concurrent application teams in migrations
- Salvaged a behind-schedule data center migration for a healthcare analytics company. Built, planned, and led production cutover to new systems. Concurrently, carved out end-user systems from parent company and hired and trained a Sysadmin
- Formal mentor of five junior resources with a focus on career progression, technical development, and professional growth
- · Informed cloud strategies for multiple companies. Developed a tool to recommend app hosting models and report on risk and reward
- Provided actionable recommendations to improve the security posture of a leading healthcare insurer by evaluating their security tools
- Expanded team capabilities by spearheading proof of concepts for container orchestrators and server migration tools.

Network and System Administrator, Safety Services Company, 2013 - 2014

The primary sysadmin for the nation's largest provider of safety training materials. Its outbound sales centers span an enterprise of two main offices and five satellite locations with 500+ users in an Inc. 5000 fastest growing business environment.

- Trained and led a team of three desktop support technicians with a high end-user to technician ratio
- Managed NOC hardware relocation and data center rack reconstruction to improve disaster recovery
- Implemented VMware ESXi with vCenter and expanded SAN storage to accommodate growth while cutting costs
- Administered Active Directory, Exchange, Dynamics, SharePoint, Lync, and user provisioning in a multiple domain network
- Orchestrated enterprise reimage of desktops to standardize and ease administration
- Instigated and managed rollout of roaming profiles for mobile users

Certifications

- HashiCorp Certified: Terraform Associate Terraform
- Microsoft Certified Solutions Expert: Cloud Platform and Infrastructure MCSE
- Microsoft Certified Solutions Associate: Windows Server 2012 MCSA
- Cisco Certified Network Associate CCNA
- Owner of and believer that everyone should feel.support

Education

Arizona State University, Graduated 2012

- Bachelor of Arts, Philosophy
- Certificate, Ethics
- Certificate, Symbolic Systems